KRISTEN MICHELLE VAN NESTE

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Rockville, MD ◆ open to relocation ◆ (301)-547-9254 ◆ <u>kmvanneste17@gmail.com</u> **LinkedIn**: <u>linkedin.com/in/kristen-m-van-neste</u> ◆ **GitHub**: <u>github.com/kmvanneste</u> **Portfolio**: <u>github.com/kmvanneste/Portfolio</u>

Motivated Full-Stack Web Developer with over 4 years experience as an Associate Certified Wildlife Biologist. Recently earned a Professional Certificate in Web Development from Rutgers University, utilizing the latest front-end and back-end technologies. Conscientious, detail-oriented, and hard-working team player.

- TECHNICAL SKILLS -

- ◆ Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- ◆ Databases: Mongo, MySQL
- ◆ **Dev Tools**: VS code, Heroku, GitHub, Postman
- ♦ Other: Git, NPM, Responsive design, Accessibility, User Authentication
- ♦ Frameworks/Libraries: React, Express, Bootstrap, jQuery, Node, ReactStrap, Material-UI, Handlebars

- Projects -

Refresh - home-refresh-app.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/hihellos/Project-3

Oct. 2020

- MERN stack application for home maintenance and upkeep to prevent devaluation over time.
- ◆ Team lead created, styled, and developed front-end with React and Material-UI. Assisted the back-end team members when necessary in order to meet project deadlines.
 - ◆ Technology: React.js, Material-UI, JSX, Mongo, JWT Authentication, Node.js, Express.js, Reactstrap

Local Grub - https://localgrub.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/eplatvoet/localgrub

Sep. 2020

- Full-stack application that promotes local restaurants based on the user's personal reviews and location.
- ◆ Back-end developer used Mapquest API and Zomato API to create a user dashboard to select,
- review, and determine the location of a local restaurant within a 20-mile radius of a chosen destination.
 - ◆ Technology: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Passport.js, MySQL

NASA Now - https://kmvanneste.github.io/NASA-Now/ | https://github.com/kmvanneste/NASA-Now/ Aug. 2020 Mobile-first web app that displays NASA's latest photographs, media, and youtube videos.

- ◆ Front-end developer effectively communicated with back-end developers to style NASA content.
- ◆ Technology: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, NASA API, YouTube API

EXPERIENCE -

National Park Service & Oregon State University, Blue River, OR - Wildlife Biologist

May 2018 - Nov 2019

◆ Studied the ecology of carnivores by trapping, tracking, and collecting genetic samples in order to draw evidence-based conclusions for scientific research.

National Park Service & Clemson University - Wildlife Research Assistant

May 2017 - May 2018

◆ Independently conducted two field research projects. Statistically analyzed data for review, wrote manuscripts, and presented results at professional conferences.

- EDUCATION -

Rutgers University, New Brunswick - Professional Certificate in Web Development

Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

University of Delaware, Newark - Bachelor of Science, Degree with Distinction

Sep 2013 - May 2017

Majored in Wildlife Conservation and Ecology, Minored in Anthropology

Publications -

Van Neste, K. M., C. K. Williams, P. M. Castelli. 2020. Does invasive common reed in coastal salt marshes impact dabbling duck food availability? *Journal of Fish and Wildlife Management*.